[Michael, Asefon Pelumi]

Software Engineer

CAREER SUMMARY

I am an experienced enterprise application Developer with (8years) skills in .JS/.TS and PHP

I have knowledge and expertise in EduTech, E-commerce, FinTech, and General Purpose Application Development.

I have eight(8) years cognitive experience in all stages of SDLC and collaborating with developers in building, managing projects. I have been developing software products for both mid, startup, and top-notch companies.

FRAMEWORK, LIBRARIES

Laravel, Nodejs, NestJs, express, PHP, VueJs, Nuxtjs, React, JQuery, Wordpress, and Symfony

Firebase, Mongoose, Sequelize ORM, TypeORM, and Redis.

OTHERS

User Experience, Project Management, Server Management, Grunt , Docker, Heroku Cloud, Gulp, Git , Linux, Microsoft Office, and Command Line Interface, Unit /Feature Testing, PHPStorm, VSCode, Sublime, and WebStorm. DevOps

EDUCATION

- Masters in Information Technology (National Open University Nigeria).
- B. Tech in Computer Science (Ondo State University of Science and Technology).

SKILLS

Good and Effective Communication, Human Relationship, Coordination, and management at all levels, accountability, meticulous with details and meeting up with targets.

AWARDS

- -Best Software Developer, NACOSS (SOUTH/WEST) 2018
- -Best Software Developer, NACOSS (OSUSTECH) 2016

No 3. Omodudu Street, Off Biola Street, Alapere, Ketu Lagos.

Contact No: +234 (0)9030844241

https://www.linkedin.com/in/michael-asefon-6730b2151

Email: pelumiasefon@gmail.com

LANGUAGES/YEAR(S)

Experience:

Javascript (8), Typescript (5) & PHP(8)

Professional Experience:

Javascript(8), Typescript(5) & PHP(8)

DATABASES:

MYSQL(8), MongoDB(4), Redis(3), PostgreSQL(1), MariaDB (3) and FireBase(3).

FIND ME ON:

NPM and **GITHUB**

WORK EXPERIENCE

Edeco Internet Gmbh,

Remote Senior Software Engineer January 2019 - till date

Stack: MEVN, Nuxt, Mongodb

I work as a Remote Lead software engineer building and maintenance of software product so as to solve human problem. Like payment system, auditing system, E-commerce. e.t.c

Tunga, Senior Software Engineer

Jan 2018 - Mar 2019

Stack: MEAN Stack, firebase

Tunga is a platform that works on various project with developer and clients, it has several applications like diagnostic application used in the agricultural sector in Rwanda to monitor **BXW** diseases in plants and give viable insight on solutions and steps to take in combating the disease in various agricultural plants.

VTPass, Sms Experience, Intern Developer

July 2017- Dec 2017

Stack: Laravel, Mysql, Node, Firebase, Angular, Ionic

VTPass, is an online payment system, which allows users to make

transcations with easy without any stress

Kezibbe Computer Limited, Software Engineer

March 2015 - June 2017

PHP, graphics, CI/CD

Kezibbe is a computer institute which I help in setting up their software workspace infrastructure and the company web application

Freelancer, Software Developer

Nov 2013 – 2015

Stack: Laravel, Mysql

Effiwe is an international NGO company which specialise in empowering all africa libraries with books.

PROJECTS

Learning center for education platform for business owner. This application is built in a Micro-Service Architecture.

Tasks carried out includes:

- I did the project structuring.
- Took active part in System Architecture design and ensure best practices are implemented.
- Design and develop the backend and frontend with my team.

Unify— Multi-Purpose Application

Unify is an application which is designed to take care of user problem with application like auditing; creating your company for auditing.

Stepwise Project — Uganda(Rwanda)

Government based project

The Agriculture based application which takes care of all farmers in rwanda which enables the government to monitor the progress of farmers and any problem faced by any of the farmer.

Tasks carried out includes:

- Took active part in System Architecture design and ensure best practices are implemented.
- Design and develop the heat map for the system.
- Design and develop point location map for data analysis.

Pixsellng — E-commerce Application

The pixsell.ng is first nigeria largest A.I driven images platform for Images

Tasks carried out includes:

- 1. Took active part in System Architecture design and ensure best practices are implemented
- 2. Design and develop the backend and frontend with my team.

Afiaanyi — E-commerce Application

The Afiaanyi application is an online e-commerce applications. Tasks carried out includes:

- Took active part in System Architecture design and ensure best practices are implemented.
- Design and develop the seller, admin portal and also help out with the other system for the application.

Tasks carried out includes:

- Took active part in System Architecture design and ensure best practices are implemented.
- Design and develop the learning management system and also help out with the other system for the application.

Efiwe — Efiwe Educational Application

Effwe is an international NGO company which specialise in empowering all africa libraries with books. I joined the backend developer's team (laravel), I actually learn for them in the process of joining them.

National Career Fair — Empowerment Application

National Career Fairs is a ccompany which has held over 10,000 career fairs nationwide and have had more than 1 million jobs seekers attend career fairs over the last 18 years. Our career fairs are the best in the nation and they have helped more people get hired through their events than any other company out there.

Tasks carried out includes:

I design and develop the registration portal for the interns, speakers and sponsors.

Zatti Educational Software — Education Portal

Zattis Education Software is an education application which shapes the fields of student information management system documentation process for educators and parents benefits

- Discovering new and vital knowledge about information
- Focus more on analysis and action planning
- Developing new scholars who will advance knowledge
- Identify trends through color coding, summary tables, detailed subscribe reports and eliminate the spreadsheets.

Tasks carried out includes:

- Managed the day to day priorities and objectives of team of software engineers.
- 2. Took active part in System Architecture design and ensure best practices are implemented.
- 3. Oversees code-quality and reusability.
- 4. Oversees and managed bug fixing during quality assurance and quality control test.

Inspire passion and drive to change the way things are made.

Intel Wireless Investment — Intel Wireless investments

Officialwebsite of Intel Wireless investment was designed and managed by me.

Osustech Mathematical Web Application

official Education Appilcation Osustech Mathematical website was designed and developed by me.

House Rent Management System — House Rent

Application House Rent Management System was designed and developed by me.

Online Recharge Application — FinTech Application

Online Recharge Application was designed and developed by me.

Rufus Giwa Polytechnic Web Application Portal — Education Application for RUGIPO

The application is a smart and e-learning application that helps to students access many resources with ease. It is in various segment the landing page website, student portal, staff Portal, and Learning management system (student will be given and will be graded by the lecturers online).